Finding aid for the Linda Garber papers, 1980-1994 LSC.1958
UCLA Library Special Collections
Linda Garber papers
1980-1994
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.1958
1.4 Linear Feet (3 document boxes, 1 shoebox)
Linda Garber is an associate professor of Women's and Gender Studies at Santa Clara University. She received her BA in English and American Literature as well as her teaching credentials from Harvard in 1987. She received her MA in Modern Thoughts and Literature from Stanford University in 1990 and completed her PhD with the same department in 1995. She has held positions at both Santa Clara University and California State University, Fresno. While the collection contains a few items relating to the Lesbian Studies Reader and other academic activities, the majority of the collection covers the publication of Garber's anthology, Tilting the Tower, documenting the collection, permissions, editing, and revising processes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift from Linda Garber, 1996.
This collection is part of an outreach and collection-building partnership between the June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives, the UCLA Center for the Study of Women (CSW) and the UCLA Library.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9969614063606533
Biography
Linda Garber is an associate professor of Women's and Gender Studies at Santa Clara University. She received her BA from Harvard in English and American Literature in 1987. She also received her teaching credentials in the same year from Harvard. She received her MA from Stanford University in the Modern Thoughts and Literature program in 1990 and completed her PhD in the same department in 1995. She has held positions at both Santa Clara University and California State University Fresno.
She has published three books: Identity Poetics: Race, Class, and the Lesbian - Feminist Roots of Queer Theory, New York: Columbia University Press, 2001; Tilting the Tower: Lesbians/Teaching/Queer Subjects, New York: Routledge, 1994. Editor; and Lesbian Sources: A Biliography of Periodical Articles, 1970-1990, New York: Garland, 1993.
Scope and Content
While the collection has a few items relating to the Lesbian Studies Reader and other academic activities, the majority of the collection covers the publication of the anthology, Tilting the Tower, including collecting, editing, permissions and revisions.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is split between materials not included in Tilting the Tower and materials included in Tilting the Tower. Material is arranged chronologically within those categories. This collection does not contain a Box 4.
Related Material
Guide to the Stanford University, School of Humanities and Sciences, Innovative Academic Courses, Records
Guide to the Stanford University, Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research, Records
Margaret Cruikshank papers
Gay and lesbian studies.; Garber, Linda--Archives; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archives; June L. Mazer Lesbian Archive at UCLA
- The Feminist Press and Lesbian Studies, 1980-1991; printed paper, photocopies, handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence with Feminist Press concerning the release of Lesbian Studies and Lesbian Studies II. Also included is correspondence between Garber and Margaret "Peg" Cruikshank, with whom Garber edited the Lesbian Studies publications, and correspondence regarding the controversy surrounding a breach of contract.
- Correspondence with Non-Contributing Authors, 1990-1993; handwritten letters, printed paper (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Correspondence with authors who were not included in the Tilting the Tower anthology, with some of the letters concerning works discussed for inclusion in future anthologies.
- Article Reprints from Contributors, circa 1990-1992; printed paper, photocopies (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Essays, published and unpublished, by contributors to Tilting the Tower but not included in the anthology.
- Calls for Papers and Proposals, 1991 February - 1994 March; bound program guides, flyers, printed paper, newsletters (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Calls for papers and proposals for various feminist and gender studies conferences, collections, workshops, and anthologies.
- Tilting the Tower: Correspondence with Contributors, 1989-1994; printed paper, envelopes, handwritten notes (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Letters with contributors concerning editorial choices, status of articles, and other business revolving around Tilting the Tower and other collaborative projects.
- Tilting the Tower: Rejected Essays, circa 1990-1992; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 6-8)
  Copies of essays considered but ultimately rejected by Linda Garber for Tilting the Tower, filed alphabetically by author's last name.
- Tilting the Tower: Correspondence with Routledge, 1991 November 20 - 1994 May 2; printed paper (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Correspondence with the publisher of Tilting the Tower concerning contracts, deadlines, advances, editorial issues, permissions.
- Tilting the Tower: Author Biographies, circa 1993; printed paper (Box 2, Folder 1)
  Biographies and blurbs submitted by contributing authors to be included in Tilting the Tower.
- Tilting the Tower: Correspondence with Editors, 1993 November; printed paper, handwritten notes (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Correspondence including editorial suggestions and grammar corrections with those involved in the process of copy and content editing.
- Tilting the Tower: Contributor Permissions, 1993; printed paper (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Permissions agreements and payment agreements between Linda Garber and the contributing authors for Tilting the Tower.
- Tilting the Tower: Proofread Drafts, 1993; printed paper (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  Annotated, proofread drafts of submissions for Tilting the Tower. Linda Garber's introduction is first, thereafter in alphabetical order by author's last name.
- Tilting the Tower: Assorted Drafts, circa 1993; printed paper (Box 2, Folder 6)
  Drafts of essays for Tilting the Tower.
- Tilting the Tower: Final Drafts, 1993; printed paper (Box 2, Folder 7-8)
  Final drafts of Tilting the Tower.
- Tilting the Tower: First Proof, 1994 February 17; printed paper (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
  Final page proofs for Tilting the Tower, with some notes at the end.
- Tilting the Tower: Published Copy, 1994; bound manuscript (Box 3, Folder 3)
  A copy of Tilting the Tower published by Routledge.
- Tilting the Tower: Book Signing, 1994 May; newsprint (Box 3, Folder 4)
  Advertisement for a book signing event of Tilting the Tower.
- Article Index, No Date; 3 by 5 index cards and dividers (Box 5)
  Index cards cataloging journal articles of interest to Linda Garber, organized alphabetically by publication, therein alphabetically by author.